Nothing in this world has prepared you for this.
Mortal Kombat is a action, fantasy film directed by Paul W. S. Anderson.
For nine generations an evil sorcerer has been victorious in
hand-to-hand battle against his mortal enemies.
If he wins a tenth Mortal Kombat tournament, desolation and
evil will reign over the multiverse forever.
To save Earth, three warriors must overcome seemingly insurmountable
odds, their own inner demons, and superhuman foes.
Liu Kang, played by Robin Shou.
Johnny Cage, played by Linden Ashby.
Sonya Blade, played by Bridgette Wilson-Sampras.
Lord Raiden, played by Christopher Lambert.
Shang Tsung, played by Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa.
Princess Kitana, played by Talisa Soto.
Mortal Kombat is a 1995 American martial arts fantasy film based on
the video game franchise by Ed Boon and John Tobias.
It is the first installment in the Mortal Kombat film series.
It was directed by Paul Anderson and stars Linden Ashby, Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa,
Robin Shou, Bridgette Wilson, Talisa Soto, and Christopher Lambert.
The film follows a group of heroes who participate in the eponymous tournament
to protect Earth from being conquered by malevolent forces.
Its story primarily adapts the original 1992 game, while also
using elements from the game Mortal Kombat II (1993).
Development of a Mortal Kombat film adaptation began shortly after the release of Mortal Kombat II
when independent producer Lawrence Kasanoff acquired the rights from Midway Games.
Newcomer director Anderson was hired based on the strength of his debut
Shopping, with a screenplay written by Kevin Droney.
Filming took place primarily in Thailand, with fight
sequences supervised by Shou and Pat E.
Mortal Kombat premiered in the United States on August 18, 1995.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the martial art sequences, atmosphere, and production
values, but criticized the performances, script, and toned-down violence from the games.
Despite the mixed critical response, the film was
well received by fans of the series.
It was also a commercial success, grossing $122.2
million on a $20 million budget.
The film was followed by a 1997 sequel, Mortal Kombat Annihilation, along with two television series: the animated sequel
Mortal Kombat: Defenders of the Realm (1996) and the live-action prequel Mortal Kombat: Conquest (1998–1999).
The follow-ups were unable to match the original film's success
and the series was rebooted with a 2021 film.
The film explores themes of island, martial arts,
monster, saving the world, magic.